Think about why I put you out there.
起用されている意味をよく考えろ
I wouldn't have chosen you if you could only play on the right wing.
お前が右でしかやれない選手ならば
私は初めから使ったりしない
I'm a professional manager, and this is how you will be assessed upon.
私はプロの監督だその判断が　これなのだよ
If you are truly a professional, then let me see you live up to my expectations.
お前もプロフェッショナルの選手ならばそれに応える事が責任になる
分かるか？　私はお前の可能性を示しているんだ
Understood? I am trying to bring out your full potential.
Don't think that you can only play well in one aspect.
自分の生かし方を一つと思うな
Yes.
…はい
All of their play goes through Zelberto.
ゼウベルトにボルを集めてきている
Murakoshi, stick close to him.
村越はゼウベルトを絶対にフリにさせるな
You're working very hard, Tatsumi.
気苦労が　しのばれるよ達海君
How can they allow a manager to coach a team without a single foreigner?
外国人が１人もいないチムを任されるとはねぇ
I will bring them to the top.
私はここで頂点に立つ！
It's Pepe.
ぺぺか！
Good, nice clear!
よし　ナイスクリア！　…ってクリア　クリアの連続ですね　この試合
We've been constantly under siege for this game.
That's fine.
ヘヘッ　いいんだよ　俺たちは点を取られなきゃいいんだ
As long as we don't concede.
What's truly intriguing is that Tsubaki has been playing without fear.
気になるのはつばき椿が　いつもより
迷いなくプレしているように見える事
相変わらずフラフラしているし
Though he's still running around like a headless chicken and couldn't catch up with Carlos,
カルロスに　体飛ばされたりしてるけど
he does play as if he has a purpose on the pitch.
何か意志を持ってピッチに立ってる感じがする
No, it's not just Tsubaki...
いや　それは椿だけじゃなくて
The whole ETU team is giving off the exact same aura.
ＥＴＵという　チム全体から感じられる
If I'm right about this,
もし　この感覚が当たっているならＥＴＵには間違いなく策がある
then ETU definitely has a plan.
ETU will start to get their game going when it reaches a certain period.
この試合　ＥＴＵは　どこかで動く
Ishihama, get him!
石浜　追えっ！
If we don't convert our chances...
いいかげんチャンスをものにしねえとよ
Will he shoot?
シュトか？
Nice block!
ナイス！　よくやったぞ！
I can't take this any longer. I'm already having goosebumps!
おお　やべえ今　鳥肌立った　…椿
Tsubaki...
That kid. He's everywhere.
あいつよく顔出すなぁ
椿！　椿！
Huh?
あれ？
あ…　あれ？このスタジアムって
Huh?
The stadium... gives off a feeling like this?
こういう感じだったっけ？
United we stand, Fly a flag!
kaze o uketomete
風を受け止めて
Let the wind blow through you
United we stand, Fly a flag!
tanabike shouri no flag
たなびけ勝利の flag
Let the victory flag trail in the wind
haruka na gooru o shinjite
遥かなゴールを信じて
Believe in the goal that lies in wait and keep running
hashiri tsuzuketeke
走り続けてけ
hibi yume tsumugu monotachi e furisosoge hikari yo
日々夢紡ぐ者達へ降り注げ光よ
Let light pour down upon the weaver of dreams
ase wa uragiranaitte kuchibiru kamishime
汗は裏切らないって唇噛み締め
Your sweat won't betray you, so bite down on your lips
nandomo tachiagari daichi o kakenukeru
何度も立ち上がり大地を駆け抜ける
And stand back up again and again as you dash across the earth
yume ni owari wa naitte me o kagayakase
夢に終わりはないって 目を輝かせ
Our dreams never end, so keep on shining
Let's start now GIANT KILLING!
For the right! Hold on tight!
My story...
Forever...
Alright! Okay!
よしよし！　オッケ！
There's always space to play into, but we can't seem to get our attacks together.
うん　行けそうなのにどうも攻めきれない
Why?
何でだ？　やっぱりリズムが良くないからか？
Is it because we didn't keep our momentum?
Hey, Zelberto!
What's the matter, Carlos?
Hey, I say, Zelberto,
I have this assumption.
Which is?
Can I just say it out?
Just spill it, Carlos!
This is not the time to be standing here chatting!
I have to say, I...
Yeah?
This match...
I'm not really enjoying it.
What's the matter? You have a stomach upset?
No, no. I don't mean that.
Whenever I try to pass the ball to you,
there's always someone there ready to intercept it.
So they've noticed.
気づいたか
As soon as I got the ball,
No.10 and No.7 will always appear between the both of us.
To tell you the truth,
I haven't provided you with a successful pass all day.
Zelberto! Carlos!
ゼウベルト　カルロス　何やってる！
What the hell are you two doing?!
I feel that our team is only able to get our game going...
when I am able to successfully pass the ball to you, Zelberto.
That's the only way that caters to our playing style.
You might not have noticed since you are always up front passing the ball.
But from the back, you could see that we haven't got our momentum going at all.
S-So that's it...
That's why, I...
will try my best to position myself closer to you!
Oh, alright.
Nagoya's trio of Brazilians... With their different abilities, they're so impressive that it's scary.
名古屋のブラジル３人組はなんだかんだで
やっぱり怖い存在だよ
Pepe possesses great pace and shooting techniques.
スピドと決定力を持ってる　ぺぺ
Zelberto is gifted with great vision and pin-point passing.
広い視野と　パスセンス抜群の　ゼウベルト
But still, the most threatening one of the three...
でもねこのチムで一番怖いのは
has got to be the nucleus of the team's defense and attack.
このチムの攻守の核
That's Carlos.
カルロスだ
25 minutes remaining for the second half...
後半２５分　前半と変わらずＥＴＵは劣勢のまま
Just like the previous half, ETU are still the inferior team.
It's exactly like what's been said in the half-time comments but...
確かに　ハフタイムのコメントどおりの展開だけど
Still, it's a terrible piece of report.
しっかし　ひどいコメントねえ広報も少しは手を加えなさいよ
The least they could do is add some fancy adjectives into it.
Anyway, if it's going to continue like this, they're not gonna win.
どのみちこのままじゃ勝てないわね
Or on the contrary... now that we've entered this period of time, why not just hold on for a draw?
それとも　この時間帯に入っちゃったら
いっそのこと引き分け狙い？
For a small and weak club such as ETU, we will be playing at a much higher standard.
ＥＴＵみたいな貧乏な弱小クラブがすげえフットボルして
We will then beat these so-called 'big teams' to a pulp. Wouldn't that feel good?
強豪クラブを　バッタバッタとなぎ倒すどうだ　痛快だろ
Just wait and see.
ま　見てなって　この国のサッカ界俺が面白くしてやるよ
I will transform the league of this nation into a very exciting one.
以上！
That's all.
What's with this guy?
何なのコイツ？　もう嫌だ私の１年間は　かけられない
I've had it!
I'm not betting my whole year on him! There's still time. I have to request for a change of clubs!
今から私は　ほかのクラブに…
いいよ
You can.
You guys can continue to believe in me.
期待してくれて　大いに結構え？
フフフン
Hurry up then.
いいかげん　あの言葉がただの　はったりじゃないって
Don't you dare tell me it's just empty words.
証明してみせなさいよ！
あ！  どうしたね　後藤君？
What is it, Gotou?
Carlos, the full-back, has positioned himself further up the pitch.
ボランチのカルロスが　今までより高い位置でプレしてますえ？
Huh?
This is bad.
こいつは　まずいですよただでさえ　ギリギリのところで
The defense is barely holding up before this.
防いでいるのにカルロスまで出てきたら
If Carlos is to push further forward, we're done for.
Zelberto and Carlos... They now have two points to initiate their attacks from.
ゼウベルトに　カルロス攻撃の起点が２つになる
Looking at you guys play with such enthusiasm,
いやぁ　楽しそうにプレする君たちを見ていると
I don't know why, but it kinda loosen me up for a bit.
なぜだろう　こっちまですがすがしい気分になるよ
They're starting to get serious.
どこかでくるぞどこかで
Has it begun?
まだか…
ハァ　ハァ　ハァ…
20 minutes left.
残り２０分一流のチムかどうかは
This is the point that separates the contenders from the pretenders.
ここからのプレで証明される
きた！きたぞ！
It's coming!
They've started!
Carlos is overlapping!
カルロスが上がった！
うわ！落ち着け！
Don't panic!
He let it through?
スル？
Stop him, Murakoshi!
止めろ　村越！
Carlos again?
ここでカルロスか！
He's gonna shoot!
打ってくるぞ！
It's Pepe!
ぺぺだ！
Listen up!
いいか　ここからが重要だかんなよく聞けよ
What I'm going to say next is important, so pay attention.
I'm predicting that at some point during the second half, Carlos will be pushing forward.
俺の頭ん中じゃ　後半　必ずカルロスは　どこかで上がってくる
Nagoya was dominating during the first half, and their passes were flowing well too.
名古屋は前半ボルは支配できるし　パスも通る
They are sure to think that they can score at any time.
いつでも得点できると思ってるけど後半
However, if the second half were to stay as it was earlier on,
同じ形で崩せないとなってくるとしびれを切らして
they will drive forward even more.
攻撃に厚みをかけてくるそうなると　出てくんのがカルロスだ
If that's the case, the first one who will do so... will be Carlos.
I-Is that ok, manager?
だ　大丈夫なんですか？　監督ブラジルトリオが　全員　前に出てきたら
If the three Brazilians were to attack, even if it's us...
いくらなんでも…シュトさえ打たせなきゃいい
We'll be fine if they don't shoot.
The opponent is an inexperienced team too.
向こうも成熟してないチムここぞって時の選択肢は
The choices they have during this situation are also fairly limited.
限られている　いいか押さえるべきポイントは　ただ一つ
Listen up.
There is only one issue here,
their best option...will be to pass the ball to Pepe.
頼みの綱　ぺぺへのパスコスだ
ええいっ！
Kiyokawa!
清川！
ホ　ホントに来た！
Th-They really did it!
Pass it forward, Kiyokawa!
前へ出せ　清川！
Prince!
王子！
し　しまった！
Crap!
A counter-attack!
カウンタ！　いけるか？　ＥＴＵ
Will this be it, ETU?
Sera!
世良！赤崎！
Akasaki!
If it's the two of them, they can do it!
あの２人なら　いける！いけ！
Go!!!
Track back, track back!
いけ　いけ！
Go, go!
Go!
いけ！
Prince!
王子！いけ！
Go!
いけ！　いけ！
Go, go!
Go!
いけ！
Prince!
王子！いけ！
Go!
I'm going.
いくよ
Don't let him pass! Stop him!
Go, go!
赤崎！勝負！
Win this!
Nice pass, Prince!
ナイスパス　王子！
I'm breaking through!
ブチ抜いてやる！
He's going for it!
いった！キパ！
Keeper!
Shoot!
打て！
えやあっ！
ぐあ！マジかよ！
This can't be!
まだだ！
It's not out yet!
えい！　…あ
うわ！やった！
It's in!
決まった！
YEAH!
しゃあ！椿！
Tsubaki!
椿！　椿！　椿！　椿！
え？　俺…　ホントに…
I... really...
ヤッホ！　椿！よく詰めてたな　お前！
Tsubaki!
You're superb!
く　苦しい…　死ぬぅ
O-Ouch!
I'm dying!
Kuro!
クロおっしゃ
Yeah!
Nice!
ナイスだ！
What are you guys doing?!
ほら　何してる！こっからだ　点取りにいくぞ
We only let in one.
It's our turn to score!
That bastard actually scored!
わあ！　やりやがったぞあの野郎！
That Tsubaki really has something in him!
やっぱり椿のヤツは何か持ってるあいつの７番は　だてじゃねえ！
He's not the team's No.7 for nothing!
It's my turn to score next time!
今度は俺が決めてやる   いや　俺がもらいっスよ
Nope! The next one's mine!
We have to defend this hard-fought lead!
り切るぞ おうっ！
はぁ…　く　苦しかった
Th-That's painful.
あ…　すいません
Sorry.
あ…　む　村越さん
M-Murakoshi.
ウス！
That was a great shot there, Baki.
いいシュトだったよバッキ
Though it lacked some elegance.
エレガントさには欠けてたけどウス！
You just have to remain the way you are now.
それでいいよ　お前
I heard you've been doing image training.
イメジトレニングなんだって？
Ever since the beginning, you've been training alone after practice.
昔から練習後け１人でボル蹴ってたらしいじゃん
All the people that you've mesmerized have always been secretly cheering for you.
お前に魅せられた人たちがここまで　お前の背中　押したんだ
That is your potential, Tsubaki.
お前の実力だ　椿　そのまま行け何度でも　しくじれ
Just continue on like this.
No matter times you fail,
all you need is that one chance to dazzle the crowd...
そのかわり　１回のプレでどぎも観客を酔わせろ　敵の度肝を抜け
and frighten your opponents.
Bring out the spirit of Giant Killing within you.
お前の中のジャイアントキリングを起こせ
椿！　椿！　椿！やったんだ　俺
I succeeded!
I did it!
やったんだ！
椿！　椿！　椿！
The scorer of the goal is No.7 of ETU, Tsubaki Daisuke!
ただいまの得点はイスト　トキョ　ユナイテッド　７番
椿　大介選手のゴルです
I can't believe Tsubaki scored that goal.
まさか椿が決めるとはね
The first half was a one-sided game,
前半から守備一辺倒の試合運びカルロスの上がり
but Carlos pushed forward...
and it was followed by a timely counter-attack...
そして　備えてたかのようなこのタイミングでのカウンタ
It all adds up.
すべて合点がいく
I wonder whether he actually planned this out,
何か　たくらんでるとは思っていたけど
But this has changed my perspective of him a lil'.
少しだけ見直してやるわよ達海　猛
Tatsumi Takeshi.
But the battle has just started.
でも　勝負はここから　名古屋の反撃を　しのげないかぎり
If they cannot hold back Nagoya's response, ETU has no chance of winning.
ＥＴＵに勝ち目はない
ハッハ！　ホント　きれいにはまりましたね
They totally fell for it!
It's just like what the manager said!
監督の言ってたとおりだカルロスのいないディフェンス陣に
We can break their defense down with a counter once Carlos is taken out.
トップスピドで仕掛ければ突破できる！
Maybe it's because Carlos is too exceptional a player,
カルロスがいい選手すぎるせいか
Nagoya is over-reliant on him for defense.
名古屋のディフェンスはカルロスに頼る部分が大きいんだ
For every move that Carlos makes, the other defenders observe and move accordingly.
カルロスが　こう動いたから　こうみたいに
１列前のカルロスを見て　次の守備を決めているところがある
Hence, they don't have to worry since they have an overview of the situation. However...
だから早めにチェックができて危険なシンは少ないんだけど
ところがどっこい　カルロスがいない時に　カウンタを食らうと
when they have to deal with a counter-attack without Carlos, their system collapses.
ヤツらは一転　ばたつくんだ
All they needed was a center-back to do the organizing,
本当は　センタバックのどっちかがリダシップを取ればいいんだけど
but even that was Carlos' job.
それすらカルロスに頼っているそれが決定的な　ヤツらのスキだ
And that is the chink in their armor.
スキがあったら突くしかないでしょ
If there is a weakness, we simply have to exploit it.
He was able to analyze the opponents thoroughly with just videos of them...
過去の試合映像から　そこまで見抜くとは
During his playing days, he purely played based on his intuition.
現役時代は　あんなに感覚的にプレしてたってのに
But now, he has really become a true manager.
本当に監督になったんだなぁ　達海
うん　うん　うんまっなに？　なんだよ　松ちゃん
What?
What's with you, Macchan?
Your expression... It's disgusting.
顔　気持ち悪いよウフン
I was unmarked just now!
フリだったんだよ　俺はよ！何で俺に出さないで
Why didn't you pass it to me?
Why did you pass it to Pepe who was clearly being marked?
わざわざ１人ついてるぺぺに出すんだよ
Are you listening, Carlos?!
なあ　おい　聞いてんのか　カルロス！よせ
Stop it.
Don't dwell on that incident anymore, Itagaki.
切り替えろ　板垣ふざけんじゃねえぞ！
Don't screw with me!
What did Itagaki say just now?
Erm... Apparently you should have passed the ball to him?
I'm unmarked, yet they didn't pass it to me...
フリでパスが来ないなんて
I'm not even considered a forward anymore.
フォワドじゃねえクソッ！　クソッ！　クソッ！
Dammit!
It has nothing to do with being on the right or left side anymore!
もう左だとか右だとか関係ねえ
I'll just aim for the goal and shoot!
ゴル狙ってやる！
That should be the way.
That is how a forward should be.
You've got find the way to believe
Carry on and carry on
Till you can see tomorrow
I'll say “never look back”
oikaze o matte
追い風を待って
Wait for the tailwind
sou chance o nogasunara
そう chance を逃すなら
And if you missed the chance
jibun ga kaze ni nare
自分が風になれ
Become the wind yourself
No fears! No tears! Yes! Let it go!
Get tough! Get tough!
Stay gold!
We'll go!
genkai oikose yuke
限界追い越せ行け
Surpass your limits and go!
kitsui hodo heart in red
キツイほど　heart in red
The harder it is the redder your heart will be!
Go on! Go on!
Stay cool!
We'll go!
asu wa mienai dakara
あすは見えないだから
Because we can't see into the future
It's time to go yamerarenai
It's time to go やめられない
So it's time to go. We can't quit!
Get tough!
Get tough! Get tough!
Stay gold!
We'll go!
tomo ni norikoete yuke
共に乗り越えて行け
Let's get through it together
mieruka It's daybreak there
見えるか It's daybreak there
Can you see that it's daybreak there?
Go on! Go on!
Stay cool!
We'll go!
yosoku dekinai dakara
予測できないだから
The future is unpredictable
It's time to go tomerarenai
It's time to go 止められない
So it's time to go. We can't stop!
The next goal will be crucial.
I won't score if I don't shoot!
Go!
Tsubaki!
Alright! Go, go!
Let them see what you've got, Tsubaki!